[ominous music playing]
[voices whispering]
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
[voices whispering]
[poignant music playing]
[thunder rumbling]
[man] Your Majesty.
THE EAST PALACE
[music fades]
[Saeng-gang] Yeom-mae? I can't hear you.
Can you please speak a little louder?
[Gu-cheon sighs]
Why is it so cramped in here?
Is this really the only place
you could hide me?
What am I. a kind of grub to you?
What is he saying?
[grunts] Come closer. And speak louder.
Through this hole.
-[Saeng-gang gasps]
-[Gu-cheon groans]
-It's probably better that I quit now.
-[Saeng-gang] Would you stop complaining?
You chose to stay in the palace
when I told you to run from here.
[Gu-cheon] I stayed because I vowed
to save you. like you saved me.
Now you're giving me a scolding?
[Saeng-gang] I had to beg grandmother to
hide you. but with this complaining.
I'm honestly about to lose
every bit of guilt and even appreciation
I had for you.
The yeom-mae…
is somewhat difficult.
so I lost my temper.
So can you…
tell me what a yeom-mae is?
A curse ritual.
A particularly vicious one.
It's the act of creating a won-gwi
by sealing a person in a jar.
[mysterious music playing]
And then starving them to death.
What if something goes wrong?
Since I cannot enter the water
to become a spirit. this is the only way.
If you accomplish this.
can you get rid of
the spirit of the Crown Prince?
[Gu-cheon] This wouldn't give me
that power.
My soul would only be able to slip out
through this small hole in the wall.
Instead. I will find a way to suppress
the power of the Crown Prince's spirit.
Then I must…
somehow manage to… to convince Father
to not kill you before then.
[Gu-cheon] Do you think you can?
What if you get thrown out after
raising your voice at the King again?
Seeing as you both have vicious tempers.
[Gu-cheon groans]
Just make sure you don't
get yourself killed. will you. please.
[Gu-cheon] You don't need
to worry. Princess.
I don’t want you becoming my companion
in the afterlife
just because you tried to help me.
[poignant music playing]
[Gu-cheon] All right. [sighs] Now.
[tapping on wall]
Please seal the hole.
[inhales deeply]
[door opens]
[door closes]
-[King] Where is he now?
-[music fades]
I can't disclose his whereabouts.
Not until you are willing to promise me
that you won't kill him.
Now that Prince Yeongan is dead.
his role in the palace has ended.
We still need his help
since the spirit has not been dealt with.
He has already failed us.
I will not give another chance
to some incompetent. lazy bastard.
You hid the truth about the spirit
and who he was truly dealing with.
[scoffs]
[tense music playing]
You have to acknowledge
it all before it's too late.
If you kill Gu-cheon to conceal
that the Crown Prince is the spirit.
then very soon.
we will share Prince Yeongan's fate.
You are expelled
from the palace as of right now.
-Leave here at once.
-That is not possible.
If you disappear.
there will be no one left to help him.
-Am I clear?
-So be it.
Then I shall expose your shameful secrets
to the palace.
How there was never a pond spirit
to begin with
because the late King's son was murdered.
Murdered by your hands. Father!
[loud clattering]
[Saeng-gang grunts]
If you do not wish to die
as your mother did.
never speak those words again.
Do you understand?
Now where is he?
[Saeng-gang gasps]
Tell me honestly.
-Did my mother die at your hands too?
-I am asking you again.
Where is Gu-cheon?
I am asking you again. Father!
Did you kill my mother?
[Saeng-gang breathing shakily]
-[King grunts]
-[Saeng-gang gasping]
-Chief Eunuch!
-[gasps]
[King] Confine the Princess
to her quarters immediately.
and make sure she never steps outside.
Ensure she's constantly watched.
[music swells]
[music fades]
[labored breath]
[munching]
[Gu-cheon sighs]
That ungrateful little bastard.
Stuffing its face all by itself.
[squeaks. purrs]
[groans]
[labored breathing]
[unsettling music playing]
[unsettling percussive music playing]
[labored breathing continues]
[music intensifies]
[Gu-cheon] A deep. festering resentment
has spread throughout the palace
in all directions.
At this rate.
even the lives of the Princess.
the King himself…
[music swells]
[music subsides]
…and Royal Noble Consort Sukbin Choi.
The Royal Noble Consort Sukbin Choi.
[tense percussive music playing]
Why are you asking about the Crown Prince
who is deceased?
[Gu-cheon] Is there anything left
of his belongings?
[Sukbin] I hid you
because Saeng-gang asked me to.
Have you called me here
just to spout nonsense?
Your goal should be to destroy the spirit
tormenting His Majesty.
Why would…
the Crown Prince
have resentment toward His Majesty?
You're saying
that the one that is cursing us
is the dead son of the late King?
It cannot be.
This explains why
His Majesty is looking for you.
[Gu-cheon] Do you wish
to lose your granddaughter?
If this continues.
your son and granddaughter
will end up vomiting blood
and die one by one.
The villagers near Goyang-hyeon
are refusing to do mandatory labor.
claiming illness?
What illness is that?
It appears to be nothing more
than a common cold. Your Majesty.
Is it true that every able-bodied man
assigned to work has fallen ill?
Illnesses like that
are very common in the village.
due to the cold energy of the mountain.
The issue. Your Majesty.
does not lie in the sick--
Your Majesty.
the seat of the Crown Prince is vacant.
I believe that you must anoint
a royal relative as our new Crown Prince--
Are you really suggesting
Prince Iksang's son
as our new Crown Prince?
At the birthday banquet
for the Queen Dowager.
did you not all see
how he fainted in front of her
and then collapsed.
or did you all look away?
Are you suggesting
I should anoint such a flawed child?
It's too early
to impart the crown on anybody.
My health is still good and strong.
so never let such pathetic statements
leave your lips!
[tense music continues]
[voices screaming]
[man 1] Your Majesty!
[squelching]
[tense music swells]
[music fades]
[King breathing heavily]
[ominous music playing]
[wind whistles]
[hinges creak]
Such hubris.
thinking you can roam around so freely.
Look at this.
This Ikseongwan was prepared
just for Prince Yeongan.
Now that child
is no longer breathing.
and you're the bastard to blame.
I will stake everything that I possess
to hunt you down. I swear it.
Because I will not be stopped…
before I catch you.
[loud thud]
[music fades]
[labored breathing]
For goodness sake.
I should have fled.
[Iksang] The King is combing
through the palace. you say?
Has he gone insane
now that his last son is dead?
It seems he's searching
for the one named Gu-cheon.
If he failed at his job.
he should've tried to get away.
[distant music playing]
[distant laughter]
How are things over there?
It's clear the spirit's power
has spread throughout the palace.
Even I nearly fainted around it.
[unsettling music playing]
So even His Majesty's life is in danger.
dangling by a thread.
But what troubles me is that Gu-cheon.
I fear he'll become
the King's lifeline at some point.
Then we should act fast
and cut that lifeline completely.
should we not?
[Iksang laughs]
[music fades]
[Chief Eunuch] Your Highness.
His Majesty is urgently summoning
your audience.
Was I not commanded
to not step outside my quarters?
His Majesty will be leaving the palace
for a brief while.
He would be happy to have your company.
[door opens]
[unsettling music playing]
[unsettling music continues]
[guard 1] Halt.
-Check the surroundings.
-Yes. sir.
[prods horse]
[Chief Eunuch] Very well.
Your Majesty.
They look like refugees.
Some elders and children
are among the lot.
Their illness appears to have worsened
as they fled.
leaving them no choice but to stay here.
It is close to Goyang-hyeon.
-I suggest we--
-I'll see myself.
[Chief Eunuch] But Your Majes…
[refugees crying]
[child coughs]
Goyang-hyeon…
I will inspect the surrounding villages.
And the memorial rite?
We'll make a quick stop.
Were you planning to go
to the late Crown Prince's grave?
I will hold a rite there.
Do you intend to kill Gu-cheon
using a memorial rite?
That won't work. I promise you.
You must spare his life
because you will need him soon.
You two stay here
and help with the people.
Let's move on.
[horses snort]
[tense music playing]
[mosquitoes buzzing]
[crow squawks]
[refugee crying]
[woman] Just try.
[resident] Sir!
Oh. wait. sir! Sir!
Wait. sir. please.
Take a look at her. will you?
Please. I beg you.
Something is wrong.
She's not responding at all.
Please!
What could be wrong with her. sir?
Please help us.
I am begging you. Could you look at her?
I can't help her anymore.
[resident] Oh. no. that can't be.
There must be something you can do.
[sobs] My dear! My love!
My love. open your eyes
and look at me. please!
[resident crying]
[sighs]
It's a deadly illness.
Is there some remedy?
Something to combat this?
Unfortunately not.
I'm not even sure what it is.
When one person falls ill.
it spreads to the whole family
by the next day.
Now the people will all have to boil
some peach branches to drink.
They say a spirit brought the sickness.
[tense music playing]
[child] My lord!
[sobs] My lord!
[music fades]
My lord!
Will you please help save my father?
I beg of you. my lord.
Like my brother…
He's not breathing.
Step back.
[child] Forgive me. my lord.
[unsettling music playing]
[groaning]
[child crying]
I'm so scared.
[King] Go with the child
and tend to her family right away.
[guard] Yes. Your Majesty.
Come with me.
The illness is malignant
and spreading quickly.
We shall return at once.
-What about the rite. Your Majesty?
-Postpone it.
We must find a way to contain the illness.
Wait.
What about the villagers dying here.
Your Majesty?
At this rate.
everybody in the kingdom is in danger.
so hurry.
-[prods horse]
-[horse neighs]
[music fades]
This is all I could gather.
It's a poem written by the Crown Prince.
Ever since he was young.
he would send me his poems in letters.
[uneasy music playing]
Now that's the only remaining item
of the Crown Prince's belongings.
[Gu-cheon] Wonderful.
Now you have to do exactly what I say.
[tense percussive music playing]
[Gu-cheon]
Go to the Crown Prince's office.
remove the door handle.
and post his poem on the door.
You must seal it
to keep the Crown Prince's power
from growing any stronger.
[Iksang] Go to the palace and find
where that bastard Gu-cheon is hiding.
[shaman] I'll begin with
the places he has already been
and trace his steps.
Even the smallest trace
will lead me to him.
[whistling]
[music swells. subsides]
There he is.
[dark ominous music playing]
[door rattling]
[shrieking screams]
[horse neighs]
[guard] We have found where he's hiding.
[Chief Eunuch] Very well. Your Majesty.
They have found Gu-cheon.
[pensive ethereal music playing]
Kill him.
-[tense music playing]
-No. please don't.
You must not do this. Father.
He is necessary.
Please. Father! Listen to me!
You have to spare him!
Father! Wait!
[guard] He's in here.
-[guard grunts]
-[Gu-cheon gasps]
[groaning]
[grunting]
[guard] Come out!
[grunts. groans]
[screaming]
[voices screaming]
[squelching]
No. No.
[breathing nervously]
[tense music continues]
[Gu-cheon grunts. groans]
[grunts]
[breathing heavily]
Let go of me.
I said let go of me!
[groans]
[Chief Eunuch] Heavens! How rash of you.
[Gu-cheon groans]
The Buddha is watching.
Take him somewhere out of sight.
[Gu-cheon breathes shakily]
[Gu-cheon laughing]
Everyone will die.
Have you lost
your mind now that death is near?
[Gu-cheon] He will die. He will… [laughs]
[laughing continues]
What are you muttering to yourself there?
[Gu-cheon breathes heavily]
The King is going to die very soon.
[music swells. fades]
[coughs]
[coughing]
[tense music playing]
[Chief Eunuch] Where is he?
He's inside. Is something wrong?
Your Majesty.
-Your Majesty!
-[music swells]
-[guard 1] Your Majesty!
-[guard 2] Your Majesty!
-Your Majesty.
-[woman] Your Majesty!
-He's not responding.
Send for the royal physician!
-Fetch him now!
-[woman] Yes. sir.
[Chief Eunuch] Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
-Your Majesty.
-[music fades]
[Queen labored] You mean to tell me
that the King is dying?
Rumors have spread throughout the palace
that His Majesty will not make it
through the night.
[uneasy music playing]
[Queen] Does this mean
that the King's bloodline
is going to be severed…
as foretold
by that malevolent ghost's curse?
[Jang] What?
Your… Your Majesty. what do you mean?
Go and send a man
to collect Prince Iksang.
[music fades]
[Saeng-gang] This is karma.
You may consider this your comeuppance
for every one of your evil deeds.
For the ones you committed
30 years ago. Father.
[wistful music playing]
I want you to tell me where he is.
[music turns tense]
Why are you standing around?
Go untie him now!
[Chief Eunuch] Untie him.
[Saeng-gang breathing heavily]
[Saeng-gang exhales sharply]
[Gu-cheon groaning]
You came here so quickly.
[Saeng-gang] Yes. I did.
You've been beaten bloody.
[Gu-cheon] If the King has collapsed.
it must mean that you're not safe either.
Are you all right?
Yes. thank you. I'm fine now.
There is something.
My father's grave condition
is not getting better.
Is there any way to banish the spirit
to save His Majesty?
[music fades]
There is a way.
The Crown Prince's body.
That's how.
[tense music playing]
[Gu-cheon groans]
[groans]
Bring the Crown Prince here.
Go and get him from the tomb at once.
Do you realize what you're asking of me?
There is no time.
It must be done to save my father.
But we cannot desecrate a royal tomb.
Your Highness.
That would be high treason--
I will bear any and all consequences
for this as the Princess. Understand?
And once Father awakens.
I will accept punishment
for disgracing the royal house.
I promise you that.
[Gu-cheon] To drive out the spirit.
we need the Crown Prince's body.
But we must not let the spirit notice us.
We will have to fool its eyes
with a dead animal.
If we fail to drive it off before dawn…
the King is fated to die.
So we must hurry.
All that remains is for me
to strike down the spirit with my blade.
[music fades]
But with the state your body's in.
is it possible?
My body's like a rag.
but I can still cut just fine.
[sighs]
Thanks to the King collapsing back there.
I get to enjoy the fresh air once more.
Are you joking. even at a time like this?
So. remember what I told you to do.
Do not worry about me.
And make sure to unfurrow that brow.
[poignant music playing]
Gu-cheon.
You told me before
that your own life matters
more than anything.
That you don't wanna die
and become an ak-gwi.
And I still feel the same way.
That's all I need to hear.
[water splashing]
And Gu-cheon.
Don't throw your life away because of me.
That goes without saying.
[music swells]
[ominous music playing]
[squelching]
[Gu-cheon exhales]
[Crown Prince sighs]
[Gu-cheon grunting]
[tense dramatic music playing]
[grunts]
[groans]
-[grunts]
-[gasps]
[coughs]
[dramatic percussive music playing]
[Gu-cheon] When I start fighting.
you must use this blood-soaked rope
to bind the Crown Prince's body tightly.
Lock the door with the rope.
And no matter what happens.
do not open it for anyone.
You must remember this.
If I fail.
you will be the next target.
[gasps]
[Gu-cheon grunts]
[both grunt]
[Gu-cheon groans. grunts]
Do not interfere.
[rope whooshes]
[Crown Prince] Do not get in the way.
The King's bloodline shall end tonight.
I won't let that happen.
There is someone else here in this palace
I must save.
[tense dramatic music playing]
[gasps. gurgles]
[Crown Prince panting]
[choking]
It's all over for you now.
[grunts]
[Gu-cheon] What is that?
[breathing heavily]
That doesn't look like a gwi-mae.
Good heavens. this is unbelievable.
Whose guardian spirit is this?
Who dares to interfere?
[percussive music playing]
[Iksang] Fine.
Let us see how formidable
the guardian spirit
you claim to serve truly is.
Show me its power.
[shaman chanting]
[snarling]
Where did he go?
[pants]
[groaning]
[growls]
[grunts]
[percussive music continues]
[boisterous screaming. laughing]
-[music turns tense]
-[grunts]
[boisterous screaming. laughing]
[squelching]
[screaming]
[music intensifies]
[boisterous screaming. laughing]
[both grunting]
[boisterous scream]
[grunts]
[groans]
[music subsides]
[pants]
[snarls]
[sighs]
If I don't know what you are.
how am I supposed to send you
to the afterlife?
[evil laughter]
[music intensifies]
[boisterous scream]
Here we go!
The grim elder!
[scream echoes]
[boisterous scream]
[Gu-cheon grunts]
[hisses]
[both grunting]
[Gu-cheon grunts]
[tense dramatic music playing]
[shaman spirit screams]
[grunts]
[snarling]
[music swells]
-[music subsides]
-[groans]
[shaman screams]
-[squelching]
-[grunts]
[ominous music playing]
[grunts]
-[snarls]
-[Gu-cheon pants]
You damn shaman. I will…
[dramatic music swells]
[squelching]
[Saeng-gang pants]
No. Something's wrong.
[Ji-yul] Your Highness! Your Highness!
-What is it?
-[Ji-yul] Please open the door.
Let me in!
Something terrible
has happened to Gu-cheon.
Your Highness.
you need to get to the pond now!
Come on. Hurry!
-All right.
-Hurry!
Your Highness! Please hurry!
-Please!
-[music intensifies]
[spectral screaming]
[Saeng-gang gasps. breathes heavily]
[both breathing heavily]
[Ji-yul sighs]
-[tense music playing]
-[Crown Prince] Do not interfere.
You know nothing.
Not a single thing.
[blades rasp]
[Gu-cheon grunting]
[snarling]
[Gu-cheon grunts]
[choking]
[shaman screams]
[Gu-cheon gasps]
[Gu-cheon groaning]
[boisterous screaming]
-[squelching]
-[grunts]
[laughing snarl]
[groans]
[shaman screams]
[screams]
[gasping. choking]
[shaman scream echoes]
[gasps. chokes]
[gasps]
[loud clattering]
[low growling]
[low snarling]
[tense intriguing music playing]
A gwi-mae is there?
[growling]
[shaman groans]
[growls]
[grunts]
[gasps]
[epic music playing]
[growling]
[groans]
[Gu-cheon] That's enough!
[growling]
[low snarling]
[gasps]
[music intensifies]
[growling]
[squelching]
[Ggeomeoksali purring]
[music swells]
[percussive music playing]
[music fades]
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today